<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Alex McKinney</title><link>https://afmck.in/</link><description>Recent content on Alex McKinney</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://afmck.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Brief Overview of Parallelism Strategies in Deep Learning</title><link>https://afmck.in/posts/2023-02-27-parallelism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://afmck.in/posts/2023-02-27-parallelism/</guid><description>Royal York Crescent, Bristol.
It has been nearly half a year since I started my first real job as a fully-fledged graduate. This has taken the form of being an AI Engineer at Graphcore, a UK-based AI accelerator startup. In quite a short amount of time, I have learned a great great deal and I am grateful for the opportunity and the patience of my colleagues – the latter of which is particularly needed when tutoring the average, fresh compsci graduate.</description></item><item><title>A New Site</title><link>https://afmck.in/posts/2022-05-29-new-site/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 09:57:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://afmck.in/posts/2022-05-29-new-site/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a hankering for a while to completely redo my personal website. There are a number of reasons for this.
For one, the old site was generated using my own static site generator sss. This was more of a project to learn Rust, rather to build a good static site generator. As such, it has not stood the test of time. Most notably, adding new features is truly awful and the HTML templates are part of the source code, rather than being separate and thus easily customisable.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://afmck.in/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://afmck.in/about/</guid><description>A picture of my hand.
Greetings, my name is Alex! I work with AI (primarily deep generative modeling and unsupervised representation learning), tinker with Linux, and explore anything else I fancy. I am currently an AI Engineer at Graphcore. In a past life I was a master&amp;rsquo;s student at Durham University, studying computer science and teaching introductory Python.
Outside of the computer-sphere, I enjoy productively procrastinating by playing piano and flute.</description></item></channel></rss>